A Guide to the Cary Reich papers FA1275
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Oral History Audio, circa 1980s (Bulk: 1982); 2
  - H-K, 2.4
    - Harding, Raymond, circa1980s; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9566)
      Interview. Harding was Bronx County Liberal Party chairman and then state Liberal Party chairman. Harding interview ends at 47 minutes, 4 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Paul Volcker until end. Volcker was an economist for the Federal Reserve Bank of New York (1952-1957) and then Chase Manhattan Bank (1957-1962). He was also chairman of the Federal Reserve, 1979-1987.
    - Harrison, Ellen, circa1980s; Sound, 140 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9567)
      Interview. Harrison was the wife of Wallace K. Harrison, who was an architect and friend and advisor to Nelson Rockefeller. She was also the sister of David Milton, who was husband of Abby (Babs) Rockefeller, who was Nelson Rockefeller's sister. Harrison interview ends at 106 minutes, 5 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Louis Lefkowitz until end. Lefkowitz was New York Attorney General, 1957-1978.
    - Hart, Kitty Carlisle, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9568)
      Interview. Carlisle Hart was an actress and special advisor to Governor Nelson Rockefeller on opportunities for women.
    - Hartmann, Robert, circa1980s; Sound, 189 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9569)
      Interview. Hartmann was a reporter for the Los Angeles Times, an editor and public relations consultant for the Republican Conference of the U.S. House of Representatives, and an aide to Gerald R. Ford.
    - Haskell, Hal, circa1980s; Sound, 157 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9570)
      Interview. Haskell worked with Nelson Rockefeller at IBEC, served under Rockefeller in the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare during the presidency of Dwight D. Eisenhower, and he was a consultant to Rockefeller when Rockefeller served as President Eisenhower's special assistant for Foreign Affairs. Haskell interview ends at 136 minutes, 10 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Fergus Reid III until end. Reid was an investment banker and financial adviser to the Rockefeller family and was a campaign aide to John Lindsay.
    - Hausbeck, Albert, circa1980s; Sound, 73 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9571)
      Interview. Hausbeck was a member of the New York State Assembly.
    - Heckscher II, August - Part 1, 1982 March 31; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9572A)
      Interview. Hecksher was a consultant for the Special Studies Project. He was also Parks Commissioner of New York City under Mayor John Lindsay.
    - Heckscher II, August - Part 2, 1982 March 31?; Sound, 91 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9572B)
      Interview. Hecksher was a consultant for the Special Studies Project. He was also Parks Commissioner of New York City under Mayor John Lindsay. Heckscher interview ends at 56 minutes, 34 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Helmuth, James, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9573)
      Interview. Helmuth was a campaign aide. Helmuth interview ends at 17 minutes, 22 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with William St. Thomas until end. St. Thomas was a Republican county leader.
    - Herter, Susan, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9574)
      Interview. Herter worked for Nelson Rockefeller when he was Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs of the U.S. State Department, and then she was chief of staff when Rockefeller was Vice President.
    - Hevesi, Alan, circa1980s; Sound, 62 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9575)
      Interview. Hevesi was a member of the New York State Assembly. Hevesi interview ends at 42 minutes, 51 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Stuart Spencer until end. Spencer managed Nelson Rockefeller's 1964 presdiential campaign.
    - Hewitt, Ben, circa1980s; Sound, 41 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9576)
      Interview. Hewitt was Niagara County (NY) Republican leader.
    - Hightower, John, circa1980s; Sound, 90 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9577)
      Interview. Hightower was executive director of the New York State Council on the Arts and then director of the Museum of Modern Art.
    - Hiss, Alger, 1982 April 22; Sound, 75 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15678)
      Interview. Hiss was involved in the establishment of the United Nations both as a U.S. State Department official and as a United Nations official. At the United Nations Conference on International Organization (the convention that created the U.N. charter), Hiss and Nelson Rockefeller were members of the United States delegation, with Hiss also serving as secretary general of the conference. Hiss and some other members of the U.S. delegation opposed the admission of Argentina while Rockefeller supported the country's admission.
    - Hiss, Donald, 1982 September 15; Sound, 17 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15680)
      Interview. Hiss was the brother of Alger Hiss and worked in the State Department during World War II. His work focused on limiting German economic interests in Latin America.
    - Hooker, Roger, circa1980s; Sound, 86 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9580)
      Interview. Hooker was deputy secretary to Governor Nelson Rockefeller and administrative assistant for Congressional affairs when Rockefeller was Vice President.
    - Hopkins, Stephen, circa1980s; Sound, 76 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9581)
      Interview. Hopkins was the director of the New York State Office in Washington D.C.
    - Horn, Francis, circa1980s; Sound, 187 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9582)
      Interview. Horn was a Dartmouth classmate. Horn interview ends 146 minutes, 38 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Frank O'Connor and Jim O'Donnell until end. O'Connor was the Democratic nominee for governor of New York in 1966. O'Donnell was an aide to O'Connor.
    - Houseman, Sam - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 48 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9583)
      Interview. Houseman was a businessman and prominent Republican fundraiser. Houseman interview ends at 26 minutes, 21 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with an unidentified female VP of General Motors until 35 minutes, 55 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Houseman, Sam - Part 2, circa1980s; Sound, 48 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9584)
      Interview. Houseman was a businessman and Republican fundraiser. Houseman interview ends at 29 minutes, 45 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with an unidentified individual until end.
    - Humphreys, George, circa1980s; Sound, 138 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9585)
      Interview. Humphreys was deputy director of Governor Nelson Rockefeller's re‐election campaign in 1970 and then appointed by Governoor Rockefeller as assistant Commissioner of Environmental Conservation for New York City Affairs.
    - Hurd, T. Norman, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9579)
      Interview. Hurd was budget director for New York State under Governor Nelson Rockefeller, and previously for Governor Thomas E. Dewey. He also served Rockefeller as Housing Finance Authority and Advisor to the Governor on Attica Prison riot.
    - Ingraham, Hollis, circa1980s; Sound, 95 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9589)
      Interview. Ingraham was New York State Commissioner of Health.
    - Innes, John, circa1980s; Sound, 110 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9590)
      Interview. Innes was a Republican county chairman. Innes's wife also appears on the tape. Innes interview ends at 88 minutes, 53 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Harold Fisher until 104 minutes, 18 seconds. Fisher was appointed to the board of the Metropolitan Transportation Authority by Governor Nelson Rockefeller in 1968. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual until end.
    - Ives, Martin, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9591)
      Interview. Ives was deputy controller of the State of New York.
    - Jerry, Harold, circa1980s; Sound, 71 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9592)
      Interview. Jerry was a New York State senator, 1959-1962, and, under Governor Nelson Rockefeller, Jerry was the director of the Office for Regional Development and then the first director of the Office of Planning Coordination.
    - Jackson, John - Part 1, 1982 November 29; Sound, 74 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15673)
      Interview. Jackson was vice president, producer, and director of stage operations at Radio City Music Hall.
    - Jackson, John - Part 2, 1982 November 29; 1/4 inch audio cassette; Sound, 7 minutes (Tape AV 15683)
    - Johnson, John, circa 1980s; Sound, 36 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15674)
      Interview. Johnson served on the Dormitory Authority of the State of New York under Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Johnson, Philip, circa1980s; Sound, 48 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9593)
      Interview. Johnson was a noted architect whose association with Nelson Rockefeller began in the early 1930s, when they both served on the Junior Advisory Committee of the Museum of Modern Artm and continued throughout the Governor's lifetime. Among other things, he designed the Rockefeller Guest House for the family. Johnson interview ends at 31 minutes, 14 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with John Debbink until end. Debbink was a long-time employee at General Motors who headed the Delco Moraine division.
    - Kaplan, Betsy, circa 1980s; Sound, 59 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 15672)
      Interview. Kaplan was St. Lawrence County (NY) Republican chair from 1970 to 1976.
    - Keene, Robert, circa1980s; Sound, 63 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9594)
      Interview. Keene was a Dartmouth classmate of Nelson Rockefeller. Interview with Keene starts at 9 minutes, 26 seconds and ends at 45 minutes, 33 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with an individual identiifed as a manager of a research department at a brokerage firm until end.
    - Kiepper, Jim, circa1980s; Sound, 40 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9595)
      Interview. Kiepper was an advance man for Governor Nelson Rockefeller during his 1968 presidential campaign.
    - Kimball, Edward, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9596)
      Interview. Employee of Venezuela Basic Ecomony Corporation (VBEC), which was founded by Nelson Rockefeller. Specifically, he managed INLACA, which was VBEC's successful milk pasteurization company.
    - Kingston,John, circa1980s; Sound, 59 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9597)
      Interview. Kingston was New York State Assembly Majority Leader
    - Kintner, William, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9598)
      Interview. Kintner was a member of the National Security Council planning board and assisted Nelson Rockefeller on the Planning Coordination Group's study on the assessment of Soviet vulnerabilities. Kintner interview ends at 91 minutes, 45 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Edward Kimball until end. Kimball was and IBEC aide.
    - Kissinger, Henry, circa1980s; Sound, 151 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9599)
      Interview. Kissinger was the director of the Special Studies Project for the Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1956-1958, and was foreign policy advisor to Nelson Rockefeller's presidential campaigns. Kissinger interview ends at 111 minutes, 17 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Charles Lanigan until end. Lanigan was New York State Republican chairman.
    - Koch, Edward, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9600)
      Interview. Koch was a member of the U.S. House of Representatives, 1969-1977, and mayor of New York City, 1978-1989. Koch interview ends at 23 minutes. Tape then contains partial interview with Albert and Viginia Callan. Albert was a Columbia County Republican leader, and Virginia was a gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Kresky, Edward - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9601)
      Interview. Kresky was a gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Kresky, Edward - Part 2, circa1980s; Sound, 273 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9602A)
      Interview. Kresky was a gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Kresky interview ends at 100 minutes, 6 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Jacob Underhill until 179 minutes, 8 seconds. Underhill was assistant press secretary to Governor Nelson Rockefeller and later deputy superintendent and then first deputy superintendent of insurance for the State of New York, 1968-1972. Tape then continues with interview with Kresky until end.
    - Kresky, Edward - Part 3, circa 1980s; Sound, 264 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9602B)
      Interview. Kresky was a gubernatorial aide to Nelson Rockefeller. Kresky interview ends at 226 minutes, 40 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with New York State Assemblymen Alfred Lerner and Joseph Kunzeman until end.
    - Kresky, Mary M., circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9603)
      Interview. Kresky was an associate of Nelson Rockefeller, worked in his personal office at the Rockefeller Family Office in Manhattan.
    - Kuhnen, Richard, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9604)
      Interview. Kuhnen was Broome County Republican chairman.
  - L-M, 2.5
    - Lanford, Oscar, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9605)
      Interview. Lanford was the president of the SUNY Fredonia.
    - Lanigan, Charles, circa1980s; Sound, 187 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9606)
      Interview. Lanigan was mayor of Rome, New York, 1959-1962, and later was on Governor Nelson Rockefeller's staff for six connsecutive years in various capacities.
    - Lankler, Alexander, circa1980s; Sound, 92 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9607)
      Interview. Lankler was a campaign aide for Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Lathrop, Churchill, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9608)
      Interview. Professor of art history at Dartmouth College while Nelson Rockefeller was an undergraduate. He went on to collaborate with Nelson and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, co-founder of the Museum of Modern Art, to develop the modern art collection at Dartmouth.
    - LaVerne, Thomas, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9609)
      Interview. LaVerne was a Republican New York State senator, 1961-1972.
    - Lawrence, Richard, circa 1980s; Sound, 87 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9610)
      Interview. Lawrence worked on the Temporary Study Commission on the Future of the Adirondacks and later was appointed by Governor Rockefeller as the first chair of the Adirondack Park Agency in 1971.
    - Lee, Gary, circa1980s; Sound, 46 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9611)
      Interview. Lee was Tompkins County Republican chairman, 1969-1974. Interview begins at 4 minutes, 51 seconds.
    - Lefkowitz, Louis - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 77 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9513)
      Interview. Lefkowitz was New York State Attorney General, 1957-1978, and the Republican New York City mayoral candidate in 1961. Lefkowitz interview ends at 74 minutes, 40 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with John Debbink until end. Debbink was a long-time employee at General Motors who headed the Delco Moraine division.
    - Lefkowitz, Louis - Part 2, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9612)
      Interview. Lefkowitz was New York State Attorney General, 1957-1978, and the Republican New York City mayoral candidate in 1961. Lefkowitz interview ends at 31 minutes, 15 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with unidentified individual discussing strategic planning at General Motors.
    - LeFrak, Samuel, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9613)
      Interview. LeFrak was a real estate tycoon and served on Governor Nelson Rockefeller's financial advisory commission of the State Traffic Safety Council and the Saratoga Springs Commission. Interview begins at 2 minutes, 32 minutes.
    - Lengyel, Henry, circa1980s; Sound, 56 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9614)
      Interview. Lengyell was Jefferson County (NY) Republican Chair.
    - Lerner, Alfred, and Kunzeman, Joseph, circa1980s; Sound, 54 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9615)
      Interview. Lerner and Kunzeman were New York State Assemblymen.
    - Levine, Louis, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9616)
      Interview. Levine was New York State Industrial Commissioner, 1966-1976. Levine interview ends at 62 minutes, 18 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Jim Cannon until end. Cannon was an aide to Nelson Rockefeller when he was Governor of New York and then Vice President.
    - Levitch and Lightfoot, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9617)
      Interview. Levitch and Lightfoot were lawyers who worked on the construction project of Empire State Plaza, also known as the South Mall, in Albany. Levitch and Lightfoot interview ends at 75 minutes, 10 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Ed Logue until end. Logue was an urban planner who oversaw numerous redevelopment projects across New York.
    - Lipset, Harvey, circa1980s; Sound, 63 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9621)
      Interview. Lipset was a Democratic New York State Assemblyman, 1957-1968.
    - Lindsay, Franklin and Margot, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9619)
      Interview. Franklin Lindsay was a White House consultant. Margot Lindsay worked with the Republicans for Progress and the Draft Rockefeller movement. Tape begins with interview with Franklin until 61 minutes, 26 seconds. Tape then contains interview with Margot until end.
    - Lindsay, John, circa1980s; Sound, 79 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9620)
      Interview. Lindsay served in the U.S. House of Representatives, 1959-1965, and was mayor of New York, 1966 to 1973, during much of Nelson Rockefeller's tenure as Governor of New York. Lindsay was a Republican who switched to the Democratic party while serving as Mayor. Lindsay interview ends at 68 minutes, 58 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Ravi Batra until end. Batra is an economist, author, and professor. Interview focuses on topics covered in Batra's book "The Great Depression of 1990."
    - Livingston, Kathryn, 1982 June 17; Sound, 37 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9622)
      Interview. Livingston was executive editor at Town and Country magazine.
    - Lockwood, John - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 329 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9623A)
      Interview. Lockwood was legal counsel to the Rockefeller family. Also served as chair of the board of the New York Public Library.
    - Lockwood, John - Part 2, circa 1980s; Sound, 39 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9623B)
      Interview. Lockwood was legal counsel to the Rockefeller family. Also served as chairman of the New York Public Library.
    - Lodge, George, circa1980s; Sound, 48 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9624)
      Interview. Lodge is the son of Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr. Lodge interview begins at 1 minute and ends at 17 minutes. Tape then contains partial interview with Sol Corbin until end. Corbin was Governor Nelson Rockefeller's top legal advisor.
    - Logue, Ed, 1982 May 11; Sound, 267 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9625)
      Interview. Logue was an urban planner who oversaw numerous redevelopment projects across New York.
      Audio becomes highly distorted and unintelligible at 140 minutes and becomes normal again at 185 minutes, 41 seconds.
    - Love, John, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9627)
      Interview. Love was governor of Colorado, 1963-1973. Beginning of the tape contains a conversation with Reich and a Rockefeller Archive Center archivist named Harold until 4 minutes, 43 seconds. Tape then contains interview with Love until 24 minutes, 27 seconds. Tape then contains partial interivew with Warren Weaver until end. Weaver was a reporter for the New York Times.
    - Lovelock, Bill, circa1980s; Sound, 85 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9628)
      Interview. Lovelock was a detective lieutenant in the New York Police Department and served as a bodyguard for Governor Nelson Rockefeller. Was a detective lieutenant in the and served as a bodyguard for Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Lumbard, Eliot, circa1980s; Sound, 47 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9626)
      Interview. Tape begins with partial interivew with John Innes until 2 minutes, 45 seconds. Innes was a Republican county chairman. Tape then contains interview with Lumbard until end. Lumbard was Special Assistant Counsel for Law Enforcement to Governor Nelson Rockefeller, 1961 - 1967.
    - Lyden, Collins, circa1980s; Sound, 188 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9629)
      Interview. Lyden was a campaign aide to Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Lynes, Russell, 1982 March 27; Sound, 81 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9630)
      Interview
      Tape is highly distorted throughout, making the interview unintelligible.
    - MacCrate, Robert, circa1980s; Sound, 234 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9631)
      Interview. MacCrate was associate counsel (1959) and then counsel (1959-1962) to Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - MacKell, Thomas, circa1980s; Sound, 94 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9632)
      Interview. MacKell was a New York State senator, 1955-1966, and district attorney of Queens County, 1967-1973.
    - Mahoney, Dan, circa1980s; Sound, 92 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9633)
      Interview. Mahoney helped found the New York Conservative Party in 1962.
    - Maiorana, Ronald, circa1980s; Sound, 281 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9634)
      Interview. Maiorana was press secretary for Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Maloney, Francis, circa1980s; Sound, 63 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9635)
      Interview. Maloney was a law partner of John Mitchell, who introduced moral obligation bonds to Governor Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Marchi, John, circa1980s; Sound, 71 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9636)
      Interview. Marchi was a Republican New York state senator from Staten Island.
    - Margiotta, Joseph, circa1980s; Sound, 130 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9637)
      Interview. Margiotta was the New York State Assembly member from Uniondale, 1966 to 1976, and Nassau County (NY) Republican chair from 1968 to 1983. Margiotta interview ends at 99 minutes, 10 seconds. Tape then contains partial interview with Joseph Crangle until end. Crangle was New York State Democratic chairman.
    - Marshall, Alton - Part 1, circa1980s; Sound, 310 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9639A)
      Interview. Marshall was Secretary to the Governor; a 1968 Presidential campaign staffer; and President of Rockefeller Center, Inc.
    - Marshall, Alton - Part 2, circa 1980s; Sound, 359 minutes; 1/4 inch audio cassette (Tape AV 9639B)